# Prabu M.S.

AVP - Sales Operations

#### Contact

#### **Address**

No:18, Kosapet, 2<sup>nd</sup> Lane, Porur, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India-600116

# Mobile

+91 7397449612

#### **Social**

msprabu116@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/prabum s

#### **Skills**

Monitor customer preferences to develop focused sales Plan

High level communication, stakeholder management skills

Proven ability to negotiate

Problem Solving, Decision Making Skills, Adaptability

Having in depth knowledge of business products

Clients and business Partners retention

# Languages

English, Hindi, Tamil, Malayalam and Telugu Performance-driven Candidate with 24+ years of experience and responsible for the management of Enterprise sales by developing a business Plan that covers sales and expense Control by setting up Individual Sales Targets in Verticals like Automobile, Manufacturing, Distillery & Beverages, Retail, Pharmaceuticals, Exporters, Food, Clothing and Lifestyle, Govt. sector with the sales team and meet those planned goals.

# **Work History**

#### 2021-08 -Current

# **Assist. Vice President – Sales Operations**

Dash Technologies and Labels Pvt. Ltd, Chennai, TN

- Developed and implemented the company's enterprise sales process, including sales pipeline management and cold calling strategy.
- Developed and Implemented new strategies for prospecting, client management and overall sales processes.
- Pay attention to seemingly Small Issues.
- Exceeded new business sales annual quota by 70%.

#### 2021-01 -2021-08

## **Assist. General Manager – Sales and BH**

Stallion Systems and Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Chennai, Tamil Nadu.

- Drove year-over-year business growth while leading operations, strategic vision and long-range planning.
- Assessed reports to evaluate performance, develop targeted improvements and implement changes.
- Initiate customer contacts and onsite meetings to develop new Enterprise accounts while maintaining and growing existing accounts.

#### 2012-11 -2020-11

# Sales & Marketing Head

Tried Pacific PNG LTD, Port Moresby (NCD), Papua New Guinea

- Responsibilities functioning as independent profit center for entire NCD Region operating from Port Moresby.
- Managed complex sales processes in sophisticated corporate hierarchies.
- Grew sales and boosted profits, applying proactive management strategies and enhancing sales Training.

2005-12 -2012-11

## **General Manager – Sales Operations**

Dash International Pvt. Ltd, Barcode, RFID, Labels

- Negotiated contracts with new customers and worked with implementation and development teams for successful field deployments.
- Leveraged opportunities for business expansions by prospecting new customers and building relationships that lead to profitable closed sales and contract negotiations.
- Developed client relationships with newly opened accounts and gained strategic positioning with decision makers resulting in the generation of sales.

#### 2003-10 -2005-11

# **Territory Manager**

Efficient Data Processing Ltd, Mumbai, India

- Barcode, RFID & AIDC Company based in Chennai.
- Involving in the process of navigating people to figure out where the product fits and how to make it successful
- Work with the customer to tailor our processed solution to their large scale business needs.
- Identification of right stakeholders.

#### 2001-01 -2003-09

# Regional In charge

Scan InfoTech Ltd, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

- Liaised between multiple business divisions to improve communications.
- Supported market expansion initiatives while implementing process improvements to execute Demand analysis and drive bottom-line growth.
- Understand the customer's Points of pain and resolve the issues.

#### 1997-05 -

## **Branch Sales Operations Manager**

2001-01

With "HIGGINBOTTHAMS LTD, AMALGAMATION GROUP, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

- A high profile Asia's Largest Book company based in the India.
- Boosted branch sales by developing and deepening customer loyalty through incentive programs.
- Increased client and supplier satisfaction by solving Complex issues with efficient resolutions.

## **Education**

**Masters of Art: Public Administration** 

**Bachelor of Art: Economics** 

**Diploma: Management** 

Organizational Theories, Job Analysis, Training and Development strategies.

**Higher Diploma in Software Engineering** 

Aptech Computer Education

Honors Diploma in Computer Hardware & Networking

*Institute of Electronics And Computers* 

Trained Certified Engineer: Barcode, Handheld And LMS Products, Checkpoint Systems Inc.

Checkpoint Systems Inc. - Malaysia